Guide to the Benoit Mandelbrot Papers M1857
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 11. Data/Plots/Visualizations, 1963-2004
  - Map of Convergence and other graphs/images (photocopies); also includes notes (Box 483, Folder 2)
  - Programs (computer printouts) by Handel, 1976 (Box 342, Folders 7-10)
  - Computer printouts - HANDEL, circa 1976 (Box 240, Folder 6)
  - Untitled folder of computer printouts, circa 1976 (Box 240, Folder 7)
  - Misc data plots/visualizations, 1976-1983 (Box 238, Folder 7)
  - Data plots/visualizations, 1977-1981 (Box 240, Folder 8)
  - Untitled folder of computer printouts, circa 1978 Mar 16 (Box 240, Folder 9)
  - Misc. data/graph computer printouts, circa 1978 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - A program to do a random walk over a square, 1978 (computer printouts) (Box 342, Folder 11)
  - Data plots/graphs/visualizations, circa 1978-1984 (Cuts from Bard Graduate Center exhibit 2012. Removed from portfolio with writing: "1979 MRL DUVAL - Discovery of M-Set 1) white paper (IBM) 2) brown paper") (Flat-box 345, Folders 1-3)
  - Computer generated fractal images for research and publication (thermal paper); LBLGraph, Duval, Lattes Super, 1979 (Flat-box 508, Folders 1-2)
  - Computer generated fractal images for research and publication (thermal paper); Brownian Motion, Attractors, 3-D Attractors, RFLINE, Hoyle Levels, circa 1979-1982 (Flat-box 510, Folder 1)
  - Computer generated fractal images for research and publication (thermal paper); Slices of Domains of Attraction, Hoyle Levels, Paper Frame/Movie Frame (Handel), other images, circa 1979-1982 (Flat-box 510, Folder 2)
  - Computer generated fractal images for research and publication (thermal paper); LBLGraph, Duval, Lattes Super, 1979 (Flat-box 511, Folder 1)
  - Computer generated fractal images for research and publication (thermal paper); LBLGraph, Duval, Lattes Super, 1979 (Flat-box 511, Folder 2)
  - Computer generated fractal images for research and publication (thermal paper); LBLGraph, Duval, Lattes Super, Superfract, 1979 (Flat-box 512, Folder 1)
  - Computer generated fractal images for research and publication (thermal paper); LBLGraph, Duval, Lattes Super, 1979 (Flat-box 512, Folder 2)
  - Computer generated fractal images for research and publication (thermal paper); includes Slices, Newton, 3-D Attractors, Julia Set, other visualizations, circa 1979-1982 (Flat-box 515, Folders 1-3)
  - Fractional Brownian surface, circa 1979 Jan 4 (Box 240, Folder 11)
  - Data plots/visualizations - LBLGRAPH ISLAND/INLAND, 1979 Jan 5 (Box 240, Folder 10)
  - Data plots/visualizations - CIRC5; Poincare, 1979 (Box 239, Folder 1)
  - Data plots/visualizations, 1979-1980 (Box 240, Folder 12)
  - Slices of domains of attraction, circa 1979 (Box 240, Folder 13)
  - "What is the shape of Britain?" circa 1970s (Box 240, Folder 14)
  - Data plots/visualizations - VOSSPLOT, 1980 (Box 240, Folder 15)
  - Misc. graphs/figures, circa 1980 (Box 240, Folder 16)
  - Poincaire, circa 1980 (Box 240, Folders 17-18)
  - Triangular 3D imaging program visualizations, 1980-1981 (Box 240, Folder 19)
  - Fortran programs (computer printouts) by Douglas McKenna, 1980-1981 (Box 343, Folder 1)
  - 2D bond percolation, 1981 Aug-Sep (Box 240, Folder 20)
  - Slices of Domains of Attraction, circa 1981 (Box 302, Folder 1)
  - "Very old Koch Island and Holiday cover IBM Research News" circa 1981 (Flat-box 346, Folder 5)
  - Fractal invariant shapes in 3D, 1982 Nov 15 (Box 241, Folder 1)
  - Fractal invariant shapes in 3D, 1982 Nov 23 (Box 241, Folder 3)
  - Data plots/visualizations - fractal invariant shapes in 3-D, 1982 (Box 239, Folder 2)
  - Slices of domains of attraction, 1982 (Box 241, Folder 4)
  - Visualizations - Slices of domains of attraction, 1982-1983 (Flat-box 347, Folder 1)
  - Computer generated fractal images for research and publication; New Fractal Cluster Model (thermal paper and transparencies), 1983 (Flat-box 490, Folder 1)
  - Computer printouts - YOGILIB/CARPET circa 1982 (Box 241, Folder 2)
  - Plots/graphs - length of Julias, 1983 (Box 241, Folder 5)
  - Programs (computer printouts) by Gefen, 1983 (Box 343, Folders 2-3)
  - Data plots/visualizations - slices of domains of attraction, 1982-1983 (Box 239, Folder 3)
  - Data plots/visualizations - slices of domains of attraction, 1982-1983 (Box 239, Folders 4-6)
  - Data plots/graphs/visualizations, 1983 (Box 239, Folders 7-8)
  - Data and visualizations by Kiyoshi Iwata, 1983-1984 (Flat-box 347, Folder 2)
  - Andrew S. Glassner - Fortran program - Run-Length Decoder, 1984 Jan 4 (Box 343, Folder 4)
  - Halftone visualizations - Shaun, 1984 Feb (Box 238, Folder 9)
  - Data plots/graphs/visualizations - M-set, 1984 Aug (Box 239, Folder 9)
  - FORTRAN - Billy Fisher, 1984 (plots/graphs) (Box 241, Folder 6)
  - Plots/graphs; calculations; notes, 1984 (Box 241, Folders 7-8)
  - Misc. plots/visualizations, circa 1984 (Box 241, Folder 9)
  - Computer program written by Serge Dubuc (printout), 1985 (1 5.25 inch floppy disk "Pascal-Dubuc" removed from this folder and placed within the computer media series for processing) (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Guder notebook, circa 1986 (Box 241, Folder 10)
  - 3-D visualizations, 1987 Aug (Box 239, Folder 10)
  - Data plots/graphs, 1987 (Box 241, Folder 11)
  - Untitled graphs, 1987 (Box 241, Folder 12)
  - Non random quadratic Cantor set, 1987 (Box 241, Folder 13)
  - Logarithmic Cantor set, 1987 (Box 241, Folder 14)
  - Random Jumps Spectrum, 1987 (Box 241, Folder 15)
  - Graphs - Levy dust, 1987 (Box 242, Folder 1)
  - Graphs - Cantor set, 1987 (Box 242, Folder 2)
  - Graphs - Random Cantor set, 1987 (Box 242, Folder 3)
  - Graphs - Cantor sets, 1987 (Box 242, Folder 4)
  - Graphs - Random jumps spectrum, 1987 (Box 242, Folder 5)
  - Graphs - Just jumps, 1987 (Box 242, Folder 6)
  - Graphs - Levy dust, 1987 (Box 242, Folder 7)
  - Data plots/visualizations - snowflake, 1987-1988 (Box 239, Folder 11)
  - Data plots/visualizations - R. F. Voss, 1987-1988 (Box 238, Folder 8)
  - Data plots/visualizations - Mark Krajecki, 1988 Summer (Box 242, Folders 8-9)
  - Data/graphs, 1988 (Box 500, Folder 9)
  - Data plots/graphs - Krajecki, 1988 Aug (Box 242, Folder 10)
  - Data plots/graphs, 1988-1990 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Data plots/graphs, 1988-1992 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Plots/graphs by Steve Quake, 1989 Summer (Box 242, Folder 11)
  - Data plots/graphs, 1989-1991 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Data plots/graphs, 1989-1992 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Misc. plots/visualizations, circa 1980s (Box 242, Folder 12)
  - Plots/graphs and articles by others - Weierstrass, circa 1980s (Box 243, Folder 1)
  - Data plots/graphs on thermal paper, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Data plots/graphs, notes, 1990 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Data plots/graphs, notes, figures, 1990 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Data plots/graphs, 1990 Sep (Box 243, Folders 2-4)
  - Data plots/visualizationsl notes, circa 1991 (Box 243, Folder 5)
  - DLA plots/graphs/visualizations, 1991-1994 (Box 243, Folders 6-7)
  - DLA plots/graphs/visualizations, 1991-1994 (Box 244, Folders 1-3)
  - Data plots/graphs, 1992 (Box 64, Folders 2-4)
  - Data plots/graphs/figures (some annotated), 1992 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Misc. fractal visualizations, circa 1992 (Box 244, Folder 4)
  - Fast Fourier transform - plots/graphs, 1994 (Box 244, Folder 6)
  - Plots/graphs by Henry Kaufman, 1994 (Box 245, Folder 1)
  - Misc. plots/graphs/visualizations, circa 1994 (Box 244, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with and fractal plots by Robin Lee, 1999 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Fractal plots by Erik Rausch, circa 1999 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Plots/graphs by Joel Flaxman, 2001 (Box 147, Folder 6)
  - Plots/graphs and handwritten notes; correspondence with Yevgeny Vilensky, 2001 (Box 147, Folder 5)
  - Visualizations by Michael Frame, 2004 Jul (Box 245, Folder 2)
  - "Initial Series of Simple Multifractal Graphs" 2006 (Flat-box 490, Folder 2)
  - Attractors of rational functions, undated (Box 245, Folder 3)
  - Binsum - FORTRAN plots, undated (Box 245, Folder 4)
  - Calculations; graphs/plots, undated (Box 245, Folders 5-6)
  - Cotton data from USDA to be "punched," undated (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Data - cotton prices, undated (Box 245, Folder 7)
  - Data - Covariance for the Nile river (computer printouts) (Box 343, Folder 6)
  - Data plots/graphs/visualizations, undated (Box 239, Folder 12)
  - Data - R/S analysis (computer printouts) (Box 344, Folder 3)
  - Data - yearly precipitation at Seoul, Korea (computer printouts) (Box 343, Folder 5)
  - Diverse programs of R/S analysis (Box 344, Folders 1-2)
  - "ERIKO TEKT," undated (Box 245, Folder 8)
  - FORTRAN plots - PARAB, SNOW, BINOM, CIRCLES, FRACTT2, undated (Box 245, Folder 9)
  - Fractal landscape (transparency) (Flat-box 346, Folder 3)
  - FRACTP plots, undated (Box 245, Folder 10)
  - FRACTT2, FORTRAN plots, undated (Box 245, Folder 11)
  - Graphs/plots - Brownian, undated (Box 245, Folder 12)
  - H. Lewitan notebook (calculations, notes), undated (Box 245, Folder 13)
  - Lichtenberger program descriptions - 1. "Lognormal Generator" ("New WIJS") a) GAUS 192 b) Tetranomial 2. Spectral Analysis (Periodogram) c) R/S analysis (Box 343, Folders 7-8)
  - "Local Gaussian," undated (Box 302, Folder 2)
  - "Long Run Rewards" graphs, undated (Box 245, Folder 14)
  - "Mandelbrot Christmas card; the quadrichrome separations of several pictures from Mandelbrot's book" (Flat-box 346, Folder 2)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research - date, undated (Box 246, Folders 1-3)
  - "ONETO," undated (Box 246, Folder 4)
  - Original art - pasted up boards; transparency (color) (Flat-box 346, Folder 1)
  - Printouts of fractal sets, undated (Box 81, Folder 10)
  - Plots/graphs, undated (Box 246, Folders 5-6)
  - Plots/graphs by hand, undated (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Plots - lines FORTRAN, undated (Box 246, Folder 7)
  - Plots - "White Noise" and "First Order Markov" (Flat-box 347, Folder 3)
  - R/F misc. graphs, undated (Box 246, Folder 9)
  - Snowflake, undated (Box 246, Folder 8)
  - SPIRAL/SPIRAX - plots, undated (Box 246, Folder 10)
  - Visualizations - 3-D attractors (Flat-box 346, Folder 4)
  - Visualizations - thermographs, undated (Box 246, Folder 12-13)
  - Wheat/grain prices - data, undated (Box 247, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous computer printouts (Box 344, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous notes/computer printouts (Box 344, Folder 5)
  - Misc plots (color), undated (Box 246, Folder 11)
  - Misc. scripts - file name lists, undated (Box 247, Folder 2)
  - Misc. graphs/plots/visualizations, undated (Box 247, Folder 3)
  - Misc. graphs, undated (Box 247, Folder 4)
  - Misc. undated computer printout plots/visualizations (Box 247, Folders 5-6)
  - Fractal images, mock-ups and cropping for book (Box 483, Folder 1)
  - Computer generated fractal images; Fractal Flakes (includes letter to Mandelbrot), 1976 (Flat-box 513, Folder 3)
  - Color fractal image with data (Flat-box 491, Folder 3)
  - Estimated Undiscovered Hydrocarbon – Comparison of Fractal Estimates with Control Methods (graph) (Map-folder 520)
  - Transparencies and graphs (Box 505, Folder 1)
  - Plots (curves, fractals) (Flat-box 515, Folder 4)
  - Data/graphs (Flat-box 515, Folders 5-9)
  - Data/Graphs (Flat-box 478, Folders 1-5)
  - Data/Graphs (Flat-box 473, Folders 1-4)
  - Data/Graphs (Flat-box 479, Folders 1-5)
- Series 12. Plots/Graphs - rolls, circa 1970-1979; These materials remain rolled because many of them are longer than can fit in conventional flat storage. The rolls are fragile and researchers should take care when rolling and unrolling.
  This series contains a set of computer printed rolls containing plots, graphs, and related data. Most of the rolls list information such as the job number, plot number, and date. Some also include the last name of the assistant who conducted the work. Assistant names listed on rolls include Lewitan, Handel, Lichtenberger, and others. Some rolls have additional hand-written annotations.
  - Plots/graphs (Box 400, Tray 1, Rolls 1-8)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 400, Tray 3, Roll 1-8)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 400, Tray 2, Rolls 1-9)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 400, Tray 4, Roll 1-5)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 401, Tray 1, Roll 1-8)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 401, Tray 2, Roll 1-6)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 401, Tray 3, Roll 1-7)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 401, Tray 4, Roll 1-4)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 402, Tray 1, Roll 1-8)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 402, Tray 2, Roll 1-8)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 402, Tray 3, Roll 1-9)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 402, Tray 4, Roll 1-7)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 403, Tray 1, Roll 1-10)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 403, Tray 2, Roll 1-11)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 403, Tray 3, Roll 1-4)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 404, Tray 1, Roll 1-7)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 404, Tray 2, Roll 1-6)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 404, Tray 3, Roll 1-6)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 404, Tray 4, Roll 1-7)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 405, Tray 1, Roll 1-5)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 405, Tray 2, Roll 1-11)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 405, Tray 3, Roll 1-7)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 405, Tray 4, Roll 1-6)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 434, Tray 1, Rolls 1-5)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 434, Tray 2, Rolls 1-6)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 434, Tray 3, Rolls 1-5)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 434, Tray 4, Rolls 1-5)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 435, Tray 1, Rolls 1-5)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 435, Tray 2, Rolls 1-6)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 435, Tray 3, Rolls 1-4)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 436, Tray 1, Rolls 1-5)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 436, Tray 2, Rolls 1-7)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 436, Tray 3, Rolls 1-5)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 436, Tray 4, Rolls 1-6)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 437, Tray 1, Rolls 1-3)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 437, Tray 2, Rolls 1-5)
  - Plots/graphs (Box 437, Tray 3, Rolls 1-3)
  - Plots/graphs (Flat-box 408, Rolls 1-15)
  - Plots/graphs (Flat-box 409, Rolls 1-14)
  - Plots/graphs (Flat-box 458, Rolls 1-13)
- Series 13. Interviews and Transcripts, 1983-2010
  This series consists of transcripts, edited drafts and published versions of interviews as well as talk/lecture transcripts. The materials are arranged in chronological order.
  - In his own words: An interview by Anthony Barcellos (heavily edited computer printout drafts), 1983 (Box 238, Folder 1)
  - Interviews for History of Fractal Geometry, 1997 (Box 501, Folders 6-7)
  - Interview, Society of Actuaries (Box 501, Folders 8)
  - Interview - Omni Magazine, 1984 Feb (Box 163, Folder 1)
  - In the Mind of Dr. Benoit Mandelbrot for Computer Pictures, 1984 Mar/Apr, by Susan D. Prince (Box 163, Folders 2-4)
  - Profile by Monte Davis - Omni Magazine: 6, 1984 No. 5 (edited drafts) (Box 163, Folder 4)
  - Interview by Anthony Barcellos, published in Mathematical People, Birkhauser, Boston, 1984 (edited and clean computer printout drafts) (Box 163, Folder 6)
  - La Galaxie Mandelbrot - Robert Allezaud, circa 1984 (Box 163, Folder 7)
  - Souvenirs a Batons de Szolem Mandelbrojt, Recueillis en 1970 et prepares par Benoit Mandelbrot, 1985 (Box 163, Folders 8-9)
  - Intervista del professor Giorello al professor Mandelbrot - Milano, 1986 (edited computer printout/photocopy drafts) (Box 163, Folder 10)
  - Como descubri los fractales: conversacion recogida por Marc Lesort (Box 163, Folder 11)
  - Interview by Mark Mahler (edited drafts), circa 1987 (Box 163, Folder 12)
  - Benoit Mandelbrot: des poubelles de la science a la reconnaissance internationale - Quebec Science, 1998 Apr (Box 163, Folder 13)
  - Interview with H.-O. Peitgen - transcript of video taped at the University of Bremen (english and german versions), 1988 (Box 163, Folder 14)
  - Natura Ex Machina, 1989 Jan (Box 163, Folder 15)
  - Untitled interview transcript, 1989 Feb (Box 163, Folder 16)
  - Speech transcript - Arnolfini lecture, 1989 Jun 5 (Box 164, Folder 1)
  - Speech transcript - conference at Royal Greenwich Observatory, 1989 (Box 164, Folder 2)
  - Time magazine interview transcript by Madeline Nash, 1991 Mar 6 (Box 164, Folder 3)
  - Speech transcript - Fractals: From Mathematics and Art to Science and Engineering - 3rd NTT Science Forum, 1991 Apr 17 (Box 164, Folder 4)
  - Mandelbrot interview (last tape) - H. Lohner, 1992 Oct 3 (Box 164, Folder 5)
  - Conversations Fractales - interview transcript, 1992 Nov 18 (Box 164, Folder 6)
  - Transkript Dr. Benoit B. Mandelbrot 1993 Jan 17 (Box 164, Folder 7)
  - Interview with Benoit Mandelbrot, 1993 Feb 1 (Box 331, Folder 1)
  - Interview - Scarsdale High School, 1993 (Box 164, Folder 8)
  - The Geometric Dreams of Benoit Mandelbrot by Jeffrey Goldsmith, Wired Magazine, 1994 Aug (Box 164, Folder 9)
  - Interview by Rolf Landauer, 1996 August 8 (Box 164, Folder 10)
  - Retranscription ecrite de l'intervention de M. Mandelbrot, Colloque Musiques de Mathematiques, Musiques en Scenes, 1996 (1 3.5 inch floppy disk has been removed from this folder and placed in the Computer Media series for forensic capture) (Box 164, Folder 11)
  - Interview, 1997 Feb (Box 331, Folder 2)
  - Mandelbrot interview transcript, 1997 (Box 164, Folder 12)
  - Transcript of invited talk: Fractals in Science, Economics and Art - Frontiers of Science, Coimbra, Portugal, 1998 (1 3.5 inch floppy disk has been removed from this folder and placed in the Computer Media series for forensic capture) (Box 164, Folder 13)
  - [Original interview by Direnzo?], 1999 Mar 14 (Box 164, Folder 14)
  - Edited excerpts from interviews of Mandelbrot conducted in Stockholm during the Symmetry 2000 Wenner-Gren Symposium (Box 164, Folder 15)
  - Edited excerpts from interviews of Mandelbrot conducted in Stockholm during the Symmetry 2000 Wenner-Gren Symposium (Box 165, Folders 1-2)
  - 'Father of Fractals' discusses 'essential' role of math in life - Yale Bulletin and Calendar, 2003 Feb 28 (Box 165, Folder 3)
  - Trent'anni di frattali: intervista a Benoit Mandelbrot, 2003 Apr (Box 165, Folder 4)
  - Interview - Mainichi Weekly, 2003 May 24 (Box 165, Folder 5)
  - Interview - Kodomo No Kagaku, 2003 Jul (Box 165, Folder 6)
  - Benoit Mandelbrot: 'The eye is not specialized' - talks with Nina Samuel, August 11 and October 12, 2004 for Bildwelten (edited computer printout drafts; correspondence) (Box 165, Folder 7)
  - A Fractal Life - New Scientist, 2004 Nov 13 (Box 165, Folder 8)
  - A Radical Mind - NOVA, 2005 Apr 24 (Box 165, Folder 9)
  - The Father of Long Tails - Interview with BBM by Hans Ulrich Obrist for the Sarai Reader, 2006 (edited computer printout drafts; correspondence) (Box 165, Folder 10)
  - 15 Salon - Benoit Mandelbrot and Paola Antonelli, 2008 Feb (Box 331, Folder 3)
  - Paola Antonelli/Benoit Mandelbrot - SEED Magazine, 2008 Mar/Apr (Box 165, Folder 11)
  - Roger Ibbotson, Benoit Mandelbrot and George Cooper - Morning Star Advisor, 2009 Feb 2 (Box 165, Folder 12)
  - Ce la crisi? Provate i frattali - La Stampa.it, 2009 Apr 3 (Box 165, Folder 13)
  - Crises there again, in the midst of peaceful phases, 2009 (Box 165, Folder 14)
  - Explaining the Wild Things - indexuniverse.eu, 2010 Feb 17 (Box 165, Folder 15)
  - C 1738: The Mandelbrot Set - transcribed from Bremen video, interview by Peitgen (edited drafts), undated (Box 165, Folder 16)
  - A theory of roughness: A talk with Benoit Mandelbrot (edited computer printout drafts), undated (Box 165, Folder 17)
  - Interview by Sylvestre Huet (edited, in french), undated (Box 165, Folder 18)
  - Interview transcript (edited, in french), undated (Box 165, Folder 19)
  - Intervista del Prof. Giorello al Prof. Mandelbrot, undated (Box 165, Folder 20)
  - Big Think interview with Benoit Mandelbrot, undated (Box 165, Folder 21)
  - Partial interview transcript, undated (Box 331, Folder 4)
  - Untitled interview transcript, undated (Box 331, Folder 5)
  - The People's Archive - Professor Mandelbrot transcript, undated (Box 331, Folders 6-7)
- Series 14. Teaching Material, 1957-1987
  This series consists of course/teaching materials from L'Ecole Polytechnique and Harvard. The materials are arranged in chronological order.
  - Course Materials - L'Ecole Polytechnique, 1957-1958 (Box 238, Folders 5-6)
  - Harvard - courses of instruction, 1979-1980; 1984-1985; 1986-1987 (Box 256, Folder 10)
  - Course - Harvard 195, 1984-1986 (Box 256, Folder 9)
  - Flip chart, presentation notes: Self Similar Statistics (Map-folder 529)
  - Flip chart, presentation notes: Erratic Chance Phenomena (Map-folder 530)
  - Flip chart, presentation notes: Very Erratic Chance Fluctuations (Map-folder 539)
  - Flip chart, presentation notes: Self Similar Chance Phenomena (Map-folder 540)
- Series 15. Certificates, Awards, and Diplomas, 1930s-2004
  This series consists of certificates, awards, diplomas and other recognitions received by Mandelbrot. Materials include ephemera, certificates, diplomas and correspondence.
  - Academy appointments (Box 466, Folders 7-9)
  - Certificates/Awards/Diplomas, 1930s (Box 237, Folder 7)
  - Certificates/Awards/Diplomas, 1940s (Box 237, Folder 10)
  - Certificates/Awards/Diplomas - Faculte des Sciences de Paris, 1947-1952 (Box 237, Folder 8)
  - Diplomas - California Institute of Technology, 1948-1949 (Box 237, Folder 9)
  - Certificates/Awards/Diplomas, 1950s (Box 237, Folder 12)
  - Certificates/Awards/Diplomas - Universite de Geneve, 1955-1956 (Box 237, Folder 11)
  - Certificates/Awards/Diplomas, 1960s (Box 237, Folder 13)
  - Guggenheim Fellowship Award, 1970 (Box 322, Folder 7)
  - Certificates/Awards/Diplomas, 1970s (Box 237, Folder 14)
  - Certificates/Awards/Diplomas - 1980s (Box 237, Folder 15)
  - Certificates/Awards/Diplomas - 1980s (Box 322, Folder 12)
  - Certificates/Awards/Diplomas, 1990s (Box 323, Folder 6)
  - IBM Fellow award, 1974 (Flat-box 353, Folder 1)
  - IBM Award, 1984 (Box 322, Folder 8)
  - 1985 Frederick Barnard Medal of the National Academy of Sciences (Box 322, Folders 9-10)
  - 1986 Franklin Medal (Box 322, Folder 11)
  - Humboldt Award, 1987 (Box 459, Folders 2-3)
  - Pace University, honorary degree, 1988 (Flat-box 353, Folder 2)
  - Harvey Prize, 1989 (Box 304, Folders 12-13)
  - Harvey Prize, 1989 (Map-folder 518)
  - Korean Mathematical Society, award plaque, 1992 (Box 443)
  - Nevada medal, proclamation 1991 (Flat-box 453, Folder 1)
  - Nevada medal, scrap book, 1991 (Flat-box 453)
  - Legion d'Honneur (Box 505, Folder 10)
  - Wolf Prize, 1993 (Box 322, Folder 13)
  - Wolf Prize, 1993 (Box 466, Folders 3-6)
  - Honda Prize, 1994 (Box 322, Folder 14)
  - Honda Prize, 1994 (Box 323, Folders 1-5)
  - The Honda Prize, 1994 (Flat-box 353, Folders 3-4)
  - Tel Aviv University, honorary degree, 1995 (Flat-box 514, Folder 2)
  - University of Bremen - Honoraray Doctorate, 1998 (Box 304, Folder 14)
  - Wolf Prize poster, 1998 (Flat-box 514, Folder 3)
  - Diploma presented by the Pio Manzu Centre of the occasion of its 28th international conference, signed by Mikhail Gorbachev, President - Rimini, Italy, 2002 Oct 20 (Box 323, Folder 7)
  - 2002 William Procter Prize for Scientific Achievement (Box 323, Folder 8)
  - 2003 Japan Prize - transcript of thank you address; Japan Prize question replies; correspondence regarding travel/coordination and congratulary correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 318, Folders 6-8)
  - 2003 Japan Prize of the Science and Technology Foundation of Japan (correspondence, press releases) (Box 323, Folders 9-10)
  - 2003 Japan Prize - souveniers (Box 323, Folder 11)
  - 2003 Japan Prize - clippings, correspondence, press materials, programs (Half-box 326, Folders 2-3)
  - Japan Prize Laureates, chart (Flat-box 489, Folder 1)
  - 2004 Business Book Award for The (Mis)Behavior of Markets: A Fractal View of Financial Turbulence by BBM and Richard Hudson (Box 318, Folders 9)
  - Award medals (Box 438)
  - Honorary degrees/awards (Flat-box 353, Folders 5-8)
  - Honorary degrees/awards (Flat-box 493, Folders 1-9)
- Series 16. Grant/Contract Administration, circa 1980s-2000s